这个故事讲的是一个普通的小男孩
This is a story of an ordinary little boy...
他叫做查理·巴克特
... named Charlie Bucket.
他不比别的孩子更快 更强壮 也不比他们更聪明
He was not faster or stronger or more clever than other children.
他的家也不富裕 没有地位以及良好的社会关系
His family was not rich or powerful or well- connected.
事实上 他们连吃都吃不饱
In fact, they barely had enough to eat.
查理·巴克特是全世界最幸运的孩子
Charlie Bucket was the luckiest boy in the entire world.
只是他自己不知道而已
He just didn't know it yet.
- 大家晚上好 - 晚上好
- Evening, Buckets. - Evening.
好 爸爸
Hi, Dad.
亲爱的 汤快好了
Soup's almost ready, darling.
还想加点什么料进去吗?
Don't suppose there's anything extra to put in, love.
哦 卷心菜最合适不过了
Oh, well. Nothing goes better with cabbage than cabbage.
查理
Charlie...
我找到一些可能你喜欢的东西
...I found something I think you'll like.
查理的父亲在一个当地的牙膏厂工作
Charlie's father worked at the local toothpaste factory.
工作时间很长 报酬也很低
The hours were long, and the pay was terrible...
但偶尔也有些意外的惊喜
... yet occasionally, there were unexpected surprises.
那正是我想要的
It's exactly what I need.
查理 这是什么啊?
What is it, Charlie?
爸爸找来的 正是我想要的那块
Dad found it, just the piece I needed.
- 是块什么啊? - 威利·旺卡的头
- What piece was it? - A head for Willy Wonka.
棒极了
Well, how wonderful.
蛮像的么
It's quite a likeness.
- 你真的这么觉得? - 觉得?
- You think so? - Think so?
我是知道
I know so.
我亲眼看到过威利·旺卡
I saw Willy Wonka with my own two eyes.
- 我曾经在那里工作过 - 是吗?
- I used to work for him, you know. - You did?
- 是的 - 他是的
- I did. - He did.
他是的
He did.
我喜欢吃葡萄
I love grapes.
当然 那时候我 还是一个很年轻的小伙子
Of course, I was a much younger man in those days.
威利·旺卡一开始 只有樱桃街上的一家小店
Willy Wonka began with a single store on Cherry Street.
但后来全世界都想要他的糖果
But the whole world wanted his candy.
- 旺卡先生 - 什么事?
- Mr. Wonka. - Yeah?
我们需要更多的旺卡巧克力
We need more Wonka bars...
- 巧克力鸟也快用完了 - 鸟?
...and we're out of chocolate birds. - Birds?
对 是鸟
Birds.
嗯...我们还要做一点 给
Well, then we'll need to make some more. Here.
张开嘴巴
Now open.
这人是个天才
The man was a genius.
你知道吗? 是他新发明了巧克力冰激凌的制作方法
Did you know he invented a new way of making chocolate ice cream...
它能在冰箱外几小时都不溶化
...so that it stays cold for hours without a freezer?
你甚至可以在大热天把它放在太阳下 晒上几小时 它都不会溶化
You can even leave it lying in the sun on a hot day, and it won't go runny.
- 但那根本就是不可能 - 可威利·旺卡做到了
- But that's impossible. - But Willy Wonka did it.
不久以后
Before long...
他打算建造一个特别的巧克力工厂
... he decided to build a proper chocolate factory.
历史上最大的巧克力工厂
The largest chocolate factory in history.
比其它的要大五十倍
Fifty times as big as any other.
爷爷 别说得这么夸张
Grandpa, don't make it gross.
告诉他印度王子的事吧 他一定很想知道
Tell him about the Indian prince. He'd like to hear about that.
你说邦德切里王子?
You mean, Prince Pondicherry?
嗯 邦德切里写了一封信 给旺卡先生
Well, Prince Pondicherry wrote a letter to Mr. Wonka...
让他不远万里来到印度
...and asked him to come all the way out to India...
造一座巧克力王宫
...and build him a colossal palace entirely out of chocolate.
将要造一百个房间 每个房间都只能用黑巧克力或白巧克力
It will have 100 rooms, and everything will be made of either dark or light chocolate.
印度 新德里
正如他所说的 所有的砖头都是巧克力做的
True to his word, the bricks were chocolate...
就连粘合剂也是巧克力做的
... and the cement holding them together was chocolate.
墙壁和天花板也是巧克力做的
All the walls and ceilings were made of chocolate as well.
地毯、壁画、家具 也都是巧克力做的
So were the carpets and the pictures and the furniture.
简直太完美了
It is perfect in every way.
是啊 但不会保持很久 您最好现在就开始吃了
Yeah, but it won't last long. You better start eating right now.
胡说 我不会吃了我的王宫
Oh, nonsense. I will not eat my palace.
我打算住在这里
I intend to live in it.
当然 旺卡先生的话不久便得到了证实
But Mr. Wonka was right, of course.
不久 天气变得十分炎热
Soon after this, there came a very hot day with a boiling sun.
王子发了封急电 要求重新建造一座城堡
The prince sent an urgent telegram requesting a new palace...
但旺卡先生有了自己的困难
... but Willy Wonka was facing problems of his own.
其它巧克力工厂 都开始嫉妒旺卡先生
All the other chocolate makers, you see, had grown jealous of Mr. Wonka.
并开始让间谍去偷秘方
They began sending in spies to steal his secret recipes.
「秘方」
菲克鲁伯开始 卖一种永不融化的冰淇淋
Fickelgruber started making an ice cream that would never melt.
普鲁诺卖一种 嚼不厌的口香糖
Prodnose came out with a chewing gum that never lost its flavor.
斯拉格伍德开始做一种 能吹很大泡泡的泡泡糖
Then Slugworth began making candy balloons...
你能吹到难以置信的大
... that you could blow up to incredible sizes.
事情慢慢地变糟了
The thievery got so bad...
一天
... that one day, without warning...
旺卡先生毫无预警的告诉工人们 工厂永远关闭了
... Mr. Wonka told every single one of his workers to go home.
他宣布会永远关闭他的巧克力工厂
He announced that he was closing his chocolate factory forever.
我会永远关闭我的巧克力工厂
I'm closing my chocolate factory forever.
对不起
I'm sorry.
但他没永远关闭啊 现在就开着
But it didn't close forever. It's open right now.
的确 有时候大人说永远 他们的意思只是很长而已
Yes, well, sometimes when grownups say "forever," they mean "a very long time."
就像有时候我觉得 我永远都在喝卷心菜汤
Such as, "I feel like I've eaten nothing but cabbage soup forever."
- 到此为止，老爸 - 工厂是关闭了 查理
- Now, Pops. - The factory did close, Charlie.
看上去永久关闭了
And it seemed like it was going to be closed forever.
但突然有一天 烟囱里开始冒烟
Then one day we saw smoke rising from the chimneys.
- 工厂又开工了 - 你回去工作了吗?
- The factory was back in business. - Did you get your job back?
没有
No.
没有人回去
No one did.
但总得有人干活啊
But there must be people working there.
动动脑筋吧 你看到有什么人
Think about it, Charlie. Have you ever seen a single person...
从那工厂进去或出来吗?
...going into that factory or coming out of it?
没有 门总是关着的
No. The gates are always closed.
的确如此
Exactly.
那谁来操作那些机器呢
But then, who's running the machines?
- 没有人知道啊 查理 - 这是一个不解之迷
- Nobody knows, Charlie. - It certainly is a mystery.
有人问过旺卡先生吗?
Hasn't someone asked Mr. Wonka?
人们后来再也没见过他 他也再没有出来过
Nobody sees him anymore. He never comes out.
只有包装好和附有寄送地址的糖果
The only thing that comes out of that place is the candy...
从工厂里运出来
...already packed and addressed.
我愿意放弃我的一切 只要能让我能再进去一次
I'd give anything in the world just to go in one more time...
看一看那神秘的工厂
...and see what's become of that amazing factory.
你不会进去的 因为你没机会 没有人可以
Well, you won't, because you can't. No one can.
这是个迷 一个永恒的迷
It's a mystery, and it will always be a mystery.
不过你的模型工厂 却能看的一清二楚
That little factory of yours, Charlie, is as close as any of us is ever going to get.
查理 让爷爷奶奶们睡吧
Come on, Charlie. I think it's time we let your grandparents get some sleep.
- 晚安 乔治爷爷 - 晚安 查理
- Good night, Grandpa George. - Night, Charlie.
- 晚安 晚安 - 椅子
- Night- night. - Chair.
亲爱的 谢谢你
Thank you, dear.
晚安 乔爷爷
Night, Grandpa Joe.
晚安 乔治奶奶
Good night, Grandma Georgina.
查理 世界上没有不可能的事
Nothing's impossible, Charlie.
- 晚安 - 晚安 查理
- Good night. - Night, Charlie.
好梦
Sleep well.
就在那个深夜 不可能的事渐渐发生了
Indeed, that very night, the impossible had already been set in motion.
全世界亲爱的朋友们
Dear people of the world...
我威利·旺卡
... I, Willy Wonka...
决定今年让五个小孩来我的工厂参观
... have decided to allow five children to visit my factory this year.
此外 其中一个小孩 将得到一份特别的礼物
In addition, one of these children shall receive a special prize...
令人超乎想象
... beyond anything you could ever imagine.
五张金券将被藏在
Five golden tickets have been hidden...
五块普通的旺卡巧克力中
...underneath the ordinary wrapping paper of five ordinary Wonka bars.
这些巧克力可能在 世界上任意一个角落里
The bars may be anywhere...
日本 东京
任何商店 任何大街上 任何小镇 任何城市
...in any shop, in any street, in any town, in any country in the world.
摩洛哥 马拉喀什
纽约
如果能有一块带金券的
Wouldn't it be something, Charlie, to open a bar of candy...
旺卡巧克力是多么好的一件事啊
...and find a golden ticket inside?
是啊 但我每年只能在生日那天 得到一块旺卡巧克力
I know, but I only get one bar a year, for my birthday.
不过生日就在下个星期
Well, it's your birthday next week.
你和别人一样有机会啊
You have as much chance as anybody does.
胡说八道 只有每天都买一块巧克力的人
Balderdash. The kids who are going to find the golden tickets...
才有可能发现金券
...are the ones who can afford to buy candy bars every day.
查理一年才一块 不可能有机会的
Our Charlie gets only one a year. He doesn't have a chance.
人人都有机会 查理
Everyone has a chance, Charlie.
记住我的话 第一个找到金纸的人
Mark my words, the kid who finds the first ticket...
一定胖的不得了
...will be fat, fat, fat.
奥古斯 这边请
Augustus. This way.
德国 杜伊斯堡
当时我正在吃旺卡巧克力
I am eating the Wonka bar...
觉得里面有一样 不像巧克力的东西
...and I taste something that is not chocolate...
椰肉?
... or coconut...
胡桃? 花生酱?
...or walnut or peanut butter...
奶油杏仁?
... or nougat...
黄油? 焦糖?
...or butter brittle or caramel or sprinkles.
然后我看了看
So I look...
发现是张金券
...and I find the golden ticket.
奥古斯 你打算怎么庆祝啊?
Augustus, how did you celebrate?
我要吃更多的糖果
I eat more candy.
我就知道他会发现的
We knew Augustus would find the golden ticket.
他每天都吃很多巧克力
He eats so many candy bars a day...
不可能他一张都找不到的
...that it was not possible for him not to find one.
是的 好样的 奥古斯
Yes, it is good, Augustus.
现在只剩四张金券了
golden ticket claimed and four more...
我就说嘛 他会是只小肥猪
Told you it'd be a porker.
多招人厌的男孩啊
What a repulsive boy.
现在只剩四张金券了
Only four golden tickets left.
现在才一张 事情会变得很疯狂的
Now that they've found one, things will really get crazy.
各种形状、大小、颜色
- of every shape, size and hue.
英国 白金汉郡
维露卡 能帮我们拼一下吗?
Veruca. Can you spell that for us, please?
V- E- R- U- C- A 维露卡·索尔特
V- E- R- U- C- A. Veruca Salt.
自从我的小维露卡 告诉我她要一张金券
As soon as my little Veruca told me she had to have one of these golden tickets...
我开始不停地买旺卡巧克力
...I started buying all the Wonka bars I could lay my hands on.
成千上万的买
Thousands of them. Hundreds of thousands.
我是做坚果生意的 所以我跟我的工人们说：
I'm in the nut business, you see. So I say to my workers:
早上好 女士们 从现在开始 你们不用去花生壳了
Morning, ladies. From now on, you can stop shelling peanuts...
你们改拆巧克力了
...and start shelling the wrappers off these chocolate bars instead.
三天过去了 我们还是不走运 糟糕的是什么都没有
Three days went by, and we had no luck. Oh, it was terrible.
维露卡越来越不开心了
My veruca got more and more upset each day.
我的金券呢?
Where's my golden ticket?
我要我的金券
I want my golden ticket.
各位先生 我不愿意看到我的维露卡 天天这样不开心
Well, gentlemen, I just hated to see my little girl feeling unhappy like that.
我保证我会不停地拆 直到我能给她想要的为止
I vowed I would keep searching until I could give her what she wanted.
终于有一天 我发现了
And finally, I found her a ticket.
爸爸 我还要一匹小马
Daddy, I want another pony.
她比那小胖子还差劲
She's even worse than the fat boy.
我觉得这不公平 她不是自己找到金券的
I don't think that was really fair. She didn't find the ticket herself.
别担心 查理 那个爸爸宠坏了她的女儿
Don't worry about it, Charlie. That man spoils his daughter.
那个爸爸这样宠自己的女儿 不会有好结果的
And no good ever comes from spoiling a child like that.
查理 你妈妈和我想
Charlie, Mum and I thought...
今晚就给你生日礼物
...maybe you wanna open your birthday present tonight.
给 拿着
Here you are.
也许我该等到明天早上再拆
Maybe I should wait till morning.
- 地狱般的煎熬 - 拆开吧
- Like hell. - Pop.
我们几个加起来有381岁了 不能再等了
All together, we're 381 years old. We don't wait.
查理 如果没有金券也别太伤心
Now, Charlie, you mustn't feel too disappointed...
不管怎么说 你至少还有
...you know, if you don't get the...
你至少还有巧克力
Whatever happens, you'll still have the candy.
唉
Ah, well.
结束了
That's that.
- 我们分了吧 - 哦不
- We'll share it. - Oh, no, Charlie.
不能分你的生日礼物
Not your birthday present.
是我的巧克力 我愿意分给大家
It's my candy bar, and I'll do what I want with it.
亲爱的 谢谢
Thank you, darling.
谢谢 查理
Thank you, Charlie.
祝福你
Bless you.
看看谁又发现金券了
All right, let's see who found it.
第三张金券被 维奥莉特·伯里格小姐发现了
"The third ticket was found by Miss Violet Beauregarde."
犹他州 亚特兰大
这些是我的维奥莉特的 263个奖杯和奖牌的一部分
These are just some of the 263 trophies and medals my Violet has won.
我本来是吃口香糖的 听说那金券的事后
I'm a gum chewer mostly, but when I heard about these ticket things...
我就改吃巧克力了
...I laid off the gum, switched to candy bars.
她是个有活力的少女 我也不知道她哪来那么多精力
She's just a driven young woman. I don't know where she gets it.
我是个嚼口香糖冠军
I'm the Junior World Champion Gum Chewer.
现在嘴里的这块口香糖
This piece of gum I'm chewing right now...
我已经嚼了足足三个月 那可是个纪录
...I've been working on for three months solid. That's a record.
我也有我自己的奖杯 瞧 像警棍
Of course, I did have my share of trophies, mostly baton.
听说有个小孩能得到 比其他人都好的神秘礼物
So it says that one kid's gonna get this special prize, better than all the rest.
我不管其它四个是什么人 但只可能给我
I don't care who those other four are. That kid, it's gonna be me.
告诉他们为什么 维奥莉特
Tell them why, Violet.
因为我天生赢家
Because I'm a winner.
多狂小女孩啊
What a beastly girl.
真卑鄙
Despicable.
你连我们在说什么都不知道
You don't know what we're talking about.
蜻蜓么?
Dragonflies?
等等 找到了
But wait, this is just in.
第四张金券被一个叫 麦克·提文的男孩发现了
The fourth golden ticket has been found by a boy called Mike Teavee.
科罗拉多州 丹佛
你所能做的就是 时刻追踪印刷出的生产日期
All you had to do was track the manufacturing dates...
以及东京证券交易所指数所派生出的
...offset by weather and the derivative of the Nikkei Index.
智障都可计算出来
A retarded could figure it out.
大多数时候我也不知道他在说什么
Most of the time I don't know what he's talking about.
现在的孩子都有高科技陪伴
You know, kids these days, what with all the technology...
杀! 杀! 杀!
Die! Die! Die!
看上去还能玩很久
Doesn't seem like they stay kids very long.
实际上 我只买了一块巧克力
In the end, I only had to buy one candy bar.
- 好吃吗? - 我不知道
- And how did it taste? - I don't know.
我讨厌巧克力
I hate chocolate.
那你他泽还去什么巧克力工厂！你这不知感恩的小...
Well, it's a good thing you're going to a chocolate factory, you ungrateful little...
接下来的问题是 谁将得到最后一张金券?
That question is, who will be the winner of the last gold...?
- 爸爸? - 什么事 查理?
- Dad? - Yes, Charlie?
为什么你不工作啊?
Why aren't you at work?
嗯 牙膏厂给我一些时间休息
Oh, well, the toothpaste factory thought they'd give me a bit of time off.
就像是放暑假一样?
Like summer vacation?
当然 和那差不多
Sure. Something like that.
事实上根本不是假期
In fact, it wasn't like a vacation at all.
糖果的热卖导致了蛀牙生长
The upswing in candy sales had led to a rise in cavities...
也就促进了牙膏的销量
... which led to a rise in toothpaste sales.
有了足够的资金 工厂开始现代化的改造
With the extra money, the factory had decided to modernize...
巴克特被解雇了
... eliminating Mr. Bucket's job.
日子真是越来越糟了
We were barely making ends meet as it was.
你会找到工作的
You'll find another job.
直到那时候 我都会好好撑下去的
Until then, I'll just... Well, I'll just thin down the soup a little more.
别担心 巴特先生 风水会轮流转的
Don't worry, Mr. Bucket, our luck will change.
我知道
I know it.
查理
Charlie.
我的私房钱
My secret hoard.
我们再赌一次吧
You and I are going to have one more fling...
找到最后一张金券
...at finding that last ticket.
你确定要把钱赌在那上面吗?
You sure you want to spend your money on that?
当然 给
Of course I'm sure. Here.
到最近的店
Run down to the nearest store...
最先看到哪块旺卡巧克力 就买哪块
...and buy the first Wonka candy bar you see.
马上回来 我们一起拆开看看
Bring it straight back, and we'll open it together.
真乖的孩子啊
Such a good boy, really.
真乖
Such a good...
爷爷?
Grandpa?
- 你睡着了? - 买来了?
- You fell asleep. - Have you got it?
先拆哪一头?
Which end should we open first?
快点就好 就像撕创可帖一样
Just do it quick, like a Band- Aid.
你听说一个俄罗斯的小孩 发现了最后一张金券吗?
Did you see that some kid in Russia found the last golden ticket?
是啊 今天的早报上说的
Yes, it was in the paper this morning.
好孩子 过来 乔治
Good boy. Come on, George. Good boy.
一块旺卡巧克力 谢谢
One Wonka Whipple- Scrumptious Fudgemallow Delight, please.
好的 给你
Okay. Here you go.
俄国的金奖券是假的 还剩一张金奖券
它让人紧张啊
The nerve of some people.
嗯 就知道金券 唉....
I know. Forging a ticket. Come on.
是金券
It's a golden ticket.
你发现了最后一张旺卡金券
You found Wonka's last golden ticket.
就在我的店里!
In my shop too!
我给你50美元和一辆新自行车 换你的金券
Listen. I'll buy it from you. I'll give you $50 and a new bicycle.
你疯了吧 我给他500美元换那张金券
Are you crazy? I'd give him $500 for that ticket.
你想要用金券换500美元吗 年轻人?
You wanna sell me your ticket for $500, young man?
闹够了没? 放了这孩子
That's enough of that. Leave the kid alone.
听着 金券谁也不要给 直接回家 懂吗?
Listen. Don't let anyone have it. Take it straight home, you understand?
谢谢
Thank you.
妈妈! 爸爸!
Mom! Dad!
我找到了!
I found it!
最后一张金券 是我的了
The last golden ticket! It's mine!
给
Here.
大声念出来听听 上面写了什么
Read it aloud. Let's hear exactly what it says.
幸运的朋友 你发现了威利·旺卡的金券
"Greetings to you, the lucky finder of this golden ticket, from Mr. Willy Wonka.
热情的欢迎您来到 现在我正式邀请你参观我的的工厂
I shake you warmly by the hand. For now, I do invite you to come to my factory...
成为我一整天的贵宾
...and be my guest for one whole day."
我威利·旺卡会亲自带您
"I, Willy Wonka, will conduct you around the factory myself...
看看这里的一切
...showing you everything there is to see."
接着 当你离开的时候
"Afterwards, when it is time to leave...
会有一列货车护送你回家
...you will be escorted home by a procession of large trucks...
每一辆车都会装着满满的巧克力
...each one filled with all the chocolate you could ever eat."
记住 有一个小孩能得到 一份意外的惊喜
"And remember, one of you lucky five children will receive an extra prize...
超乎你的想象
...beyond your wildest imagination.
下面是说明
Now, here are your instructions."
2月1日早10点 你们必须在工厂门前集合
"On the 1 st of February, you must come to the factory gates at 10 a.m. Sharp.
可以由一个大人陪伴
You're allowed to bring one member of your family to look after you.
那时 威利·旺卡
Until then, Willy Wonka."
2月1日
The 1 st of February.
- 那不就是明天吗? - 那抓紧啊
- But that's tomorrow. - Then there's not a moment to lose.
查理 快去洗脸刷牙梳头
Wash your face, comb your hair, scrub your hands, brush your teeth, blow your nose.
- 脱掉你的泥裤子 - 我们必须先冷静下来
- And get that mud off your pants. - Now we must all try and keep very calm.
首先我们得决定 谁和查理一起去
First thing that we have to decide is this: Who is going with Charlie to the factory?
我去 我会照顾他 你把他交给我吧
I will. I'll take him. You leave it to me.
亲爱的 你去怎么样? 你觉得你该去吗?
How about you, dear? Don't you think you ought to go?
乔爷爷似乎知道的更多
Well, Grandpa Joe seems to know more about it than we do, and...
而且看上去身体也很好
Provided, of course, he feels well enough.
不 我们不能去
No. We're not going.
一位女士愿意出500美元买那张金券
A woman offered me $500 for the ticket.
一定会有人愿意出更多的钱的
I bet someone else would pay more.
我们更需要钱 而不是巧克力
We need the money more than we need the chocolate.
孩子 过来
Young man, come here.
世界上有那么多的钱
There's plenty of money out there.
他们天天在印
They print more every day.
但这金券
But this ticket...
世界上也只有五张
...there's only five of them in the whole world...
不会再有了
...and that's all there's ever going to be.
只有笨蛋才会用这个换钱
Only a dummy would give this up for something as common as money.
你是笨蛋吗?
Are you a dummy?
不 先生
No, sir.
那就准备准备吧 去工厂了
Then get that mud off your pants. You've got a factory to go to.
爸爸 我要进去
Daddy, I want to go in.
才9点59分呢 宝贝
It's 9:59, sweetheart.
让时间走快点!
Make time go faster.
你觉得旺卡先生认得出你吗?
Do you think Mr. Wonka will recognize you?
难说 已经很多年了
Hard to say. It's been years.
维奥莉特 紧盯着奖品啊!
Eyes on the prize, Violet.
紧盯着奖品啊
Eyes on the prize.
欢迎 请进
Please enter.
请向前走
Come forward.
关门
Close the gates.
亲爱的游客
Dear visitors...
欢迎来我旺卡工厂
... it is my great pleasure to welcome you to my humble factory.
我是谁?
And who am I?
嗯...
Well...
威利·旺卡 威利·旺卡
Willy Wonka, Willy Wonka
一个伟大的巧克力匠
The amazing chocolatier
威利·旺卡 威利·旺卡
Willy Wonka, Willy Wonka
人人都鼓掌吧 万岁!
Everybody give a cheer! Hooray!
他谦虚聪明又潇洒
He's modest, clever and so smart
并且才华横溢
He barely can restrain it
他那么慷慨
With so much generosity
没人能限制他
There is no way to contain it!
限制他 限制他! 限制他! 限制他!
To contain it To contain, to contain, to contain!
万岁!
Hooray!
威利·旺卡 威利·旺卡
Willy Wonka, Willy Wonka
你们马上就要看到他
He's the one that you're about to meet
威利·旺卡 威利·旺卡
Willy Wonka, Willy Wonka
他是个不可打败的天才
He's the genius who just can't be beat
魔术师和巧克力匠
The magician and the chocolate wiz
他过着简朴的生活
The best darn guy who ever lived
威利·旺卡 他就在这儿!
Willy Wonka, here he is!
奇妙的巧克力啊
The amazing chocolatier
这不壮观吗?
Wasn't that just magnificent?
我还以为中间就会 撑不下去了 没想到撑到了最后
I was worried it was getting a little dodgy in the middle part, but then that finale...
你是谁?
Who are you?
- 他是威利·旺卡 - 真的?
- He's Willy Wonka. - Really?
早上好 晨星们
"Good morning, starshine.
地球在向你们问好呢
The Earth says hello."
游客们 你们好
"Dear guests, greetings.
欢迎来到工厂 我热情的和你们握手
Welcome to the factory. I shake you warmly by the hand.
我叫威利·旺卡
My name is Willy Wonka."
那你不应该在那儿吗? (指舞台上)
Then shouldn't you be up there?
那我就不能很好的看表演了 对吧?
I couldn't very well watch the show from up there, now, could I, little girl?
旺卡先生 我不知道你还记得我吗
Mr. Wonka, I don't know if you'll remember me...
我以前在你的工厂工作过
...but I used to work here in the factory.
那你是那个可恶的间谍吗?
Were you one of those despicable spies who tried to steal...
偷走我辛苦的工作成果 卖给那些卑鄙的寄生虫工厂
...my life's work and sell it to parasitic, copycat, candy- making cads?
不是的
No, sir.
很好 那欢迎回来
Then wonderful. Welcome back.
走吧 孩子们
Let's get a move on, kids.
你难道不想知道我们的名字吗?
Don't you want to know our names?
不知道那有什么关系 快 不然要错过了
Can't imagine how it would matter. Come quickly. Far too much to see.
把衣服脱了吧
Just drop your coats anywhere.
- 旺卡先生 真热啊 - 什么?
- Mr. Wonka? Sure is toasty in here. - What?
哦 我必需保持温度 因为我的工人习惯在炎热的天气下工作
I have to keep it warm in here. My workers are used to an extremely hot climate.
他们受不了冷
They just can't stand the cold.
那谁是工人?
Who are the workers?
问的真是时候
All in good time. Now...
旺卡先生 我是维奥里特·伯里格
Mr. Wonka, I'm Violet Beauregarde.
- 我不在乎 - 你应该在乎
- I don't care. - Well, you should care.
因为那个拿特别奖的就是我
Because I'm gonna win the special prize at the end.
你很自信啊 自信是关键
Well, you do seem confident, and confidence is key.
我是维露卡·索尔特 很高兴见到你
I'm Veruca Salt. It's very nice to meet you, sir.
我一直以为维露卡是一种
I always thought a verruca was a type of wart...
长在脚上的疣
...you got on the bottom of your foot.
我是奥古斯特 我喜欢你做的巧克力
I am Augustus Gloop. I love your chocolate.
看的出来 我也喜欢
I can see that. So do I.
从来没想到 我们有那么多共同点啊
I never expected to have so much in common.
你 麦克·提文
You. You're Mike Teavee.
那个破解系统的小魔鬼
You're the little devil who cracked the system.
而你 你只是个幸运儿 对吗?
And you. Well, you're just lucky to be here, aren't you?
其他人就是他们的....
And the rest of you must be their...
- 家长 - 是的
- Parents. - Yeah.
妈妈和爸爸
Moms and dads.
爸爸?
Dad?
Papa?
好了 我们走吧
Okay, then. Let's move along.
是我的错觉 还是旺卡看上去有些神经质
ls it just me or does Wonka seem a few quarters short of a buck?
抱歉 不予评论
l'm sorry, l don't speak American.
- 你要些巧克力吗? - 好的
- Would you like some chocolate? - Sure.
那你应该自己带一些来
Then you should've brought some.
- 我们做个朋友吧 - 最好的朋友
- Let's be friends. - Best friends.
这是一个很重要的车间
An important room, this.
- 毕竟这是座巧克力工厂 - 那为什么门这么小
- After all, it is a chocolate factory. - Then why is the door so small?
可以让巧克力的味道留在里面啊
That's to keep all the great big chocolatey flavor inside.
听着 孩子们 别走丢了
Now, do be careful, my dear children.
别失去理智
Don't lose your heads.
也不要过度太兴奋了
Don't get overexcited.
保持冷静
Just keep very calm.
太美了
It's beautiful.
什么?
What?
哦 是很美
Oh, yeah, it's very beautiful.
河里的每一滴都是
Every drop of the river...
最上乘的热巧克力
...is hot, melted chocolate of the finest quality.
瀑布是最重要的
The waterfall is most important.
能不停地搅拌巧克力
Mixes the chocolate.
把它变得爽口、松脆
Churns it up. Makes it light and frothy.
顺便说一下
By the way...
世界上还没有一个工厂用瀑布来搅拌巧克力 亲爱的孩子们
...no other factory in the world mixes its chocolate by waterfall, my dear children.
这可是千真万确的
And you can take that to the bank.
注意
People.
这些吸管
Those pipes...
会把巧克力吸上来 并带到工厂的各个角落
...suck up the chocolate and carry it away all over the factory.
一小时有几千加仑
Thousands of gallons an hour. Yeah.
喜欢我的草地吗? 尝尝我的草吧
And do you like my meadow? Try some of my grass.
割点吧 非常新鲜 非常漂亮
Please have a blade. Please do. It's so delectable and so darn good- Iooking.
这草真的能吃?
You can eat the grass?
当然
Of course you can.
这房间的每样东西都能吃
Everything in this room is eatable.
我也是可以吃的
Even I'm eatable.
不过那是食人族 孩子们
But that is called cannibalism, my dear children...
是大多数社会都坚决反对的
...and is, in fact, frowned upon in most societies.
嗯
Yeah.
尽情玩吧
Enjoy.
继续 走吧 快点
Go on. Scoot, scoot.
儿子
Son.
别这样
Please.
爸爸 他说过尽情玩吧
Dad, he said, "Enjoy."
为什么不把它扔了 换一块新的口香糖
Why hold on to it? Why not start a new piece?
因为那样我就不是赢家 会成为失败者、像你一样
Because then I wouldn't be a champion. I'd be a loser, like you.
爸爸 看那儿
Daddy, look over there.
是什么?
What is it?
是个小人
It's a little person.
那边 瀑布旁
Over there, by the waterfall.
- 有两个 - 不止两个
- There's two of them. - There's more than two.
- 他们从哪里来啊? - 是什么人啊?
- Where do they come from? - Who are they?
他们是真的人吗?
Are they real people?
当然是真的人了 他们是欧伦比人
Of course they're real people. They're Oompa- Loompas.
- 欧伦比人? - 进口的 直接从伦比兰进口的
- Oompa- Loompas? - Imported, direct from Loompaland.
- 世界上没有这样一个地方 - 什么?
- There's no such place. - What?
旺卡先生 我在高中教地理 我告诉你...
Mr. Wonka, I teach high- school geography, and I'm here to tell you...
那我告诉你那个国家 它是个恐怖的地方
Well, then you'll know all about it, and, oh, what a terrible country it is.
那是一个灌木从生 充满野兽的地方
The whole place is nothing but thick jungles...
各种可怕的虫子 巨毒的飞虫
... infested by the most dangerous beasts in the entire world.
还有些可怕恶心的东西
Hornswogglers and snozzwangers and those terrible, wicked whangdoodles.
我去那儿为了寻找 一种新奇的糖果口味
I went to Loompaland looking for exotic new flavors for candy.
但是
Instead...
但我却发现了欧伦比人
... I found the Oompa- Loompas.
他们住在树上的房子里 来躲避各种野兽
They lived in tree houses to escape from the fierce creatures who lived below.
他们什么都不吃除了恶心的绿毛毛虫
The Oompa- Loompas ate nothing but green caterpillars, which tasted revolting.
他们把虫子和别的东西
The Oompa- Loompas looked for other things...
放在一起拈碎 使味道变的很好
... to mash up with the caterpillars to make them taste better:
红甲壳虫 棒棒树皮
Red beetles, the bark of the bong- bong tree.
都很恶心
All of them beastly...
但毛毛虫才是最恶心的
... but not quite so beastly as the caterpillars.
但他们最喜欢吃的是可可豆
But the food they longed for the most was the cocoa bean.
他们一年只要能发现 三四个可可豆就很开心了
An Oompa- Loompa was lucky if he found three or four cocoa beans a year.
他们多渴望它啊
But, oh, how they craved them.
他们整天就想着可可豆
All they'd ever think about was cocoa beans.
可可豆是巧克力的基本成份 于是我告诉他们的首领
The cocoa bean is the thing from which chocolate is made, so I told the chief:
到我的工厂来吧 那儿有很多可可豆 你为我工作
我用可可豆作为报酬
他们都是勤劳的工人
They are such wonderful workers.
但我警告你们 他们很顽皮
I feel I must warn you, though, they are rather mischievous.
总是在开玩笑
Always making jokes.
奥古斯 我的宝贝 别那样做啊
Augustus, my child, that is not a good thing you do!
嗨 小朋友
Hey, little boy.
我的巧克力不能用人的手碰的
My chocolate must be untouched by human hands.
他会被淹死的
He'll drown.
他不会游泳
He can't swim.
救救他啊
Save him!
奥古斯! 不!
Augustus! No!
奥古斯!
Augustus!
奥古斯! 小心
Augustus, watch out!
他被吸上去了
There he goes.
快叫消防队
Call the fire brigade!
那根管子真是惊人的粗
It's a wonder how that pipe is big enough.
它还不够粗 他停下来了
It isn't big enough. He's slowing down.
他会卡住的
He's gonna stick.
我想他已经卡住了
I think he has.
他已经堵住管子了
He's blocked the whole pipe.
看 那是欧伦比人
Look. The Oompa- Loompas.
别靠近我 怪胎
Back off, you little freaks!
他们在做什么?
What are they doing?
我想他们要给我们唱歌呢 这不多见
They're going to treat us to a little song. It is quite a special occasion.
他们已经很久没有新客人了
They haven't had a fresh audience in many a moon.
奥古斯特·格鲁普 奥古斯特·格鲁普
Augustus Gloop, Augustus Gloop
一个愚蠢、贪心的大傻蛋
The great big, greedy nincompoop
奥古斯特·格鲁普 又胖又坏 贪心、下流又幼稚
Augustus Gloop, so big and vile So greedy, foul and infantile
我们大叫"开始吧" 时机已经成熟了
"Come on!" we cried "The time is ripe
把他送上吸管里
To send him shooting up the pipe!"
等等 孩子们 提醒一下
But don't, dear children, be alarmed
奥古斯特·格鲁普不会受伤的
Augustus Gloop will not be harmed
不过我们必须承认
Although, of course, we must admit
他会小小的变点形
He will be altered quite a bit
慢慢 轮子一圈又一圈地转
Slowly, wheels go round and round
齿轮慢慢开始启动
And cogs begin to grind and pound
我们煮他一分多钟
We'll boil him for a minute more
直到我们完全确信
Until we're absolutely sure
然后他来了 优雅的神
Then out he comes, by God, by grace
奇迹发生了
A miracle has taken place
这么贪吃的小男孩
This greedy brute, this louse's ear
却人人喜爱
Is loved by people everywhere
如果你讨厌
For who could hate or bear a grudge
就不要吃这甘甜的软糖
Against a luscious bit of fudge?
好极了 怎么样 他们唱得好吧
Bravo! Well done!
他们多快乐啊 他们多迷人啊
Aren't they delightful? Aren't they charming?
- 我想他们预演过 - 他们知道我们要来
- I do say, that all seemed rather rehearsed. - Like they knew it was gonna happen.
瞎说
Oh, poppycock.
我的儿子呢? 那管子去哪里了?
Where is my son? Where does that pipe go to?
那管子去了...
That pipe, it just so happens to lead...
我做香甜巧克力的房间
...directly to the room where I make delicious...
是草莓巧克力软糖车间
...strawberry- flavored, chocolate- coated fudge.
那他会被做成草莓巧克力软糖
Then he will be made into strawberry- flavored, chocolate- coated fudge.
然后被称斤卖到全世界吗?
They'll be selling him by the pound all over the world?
不 那不行 味道会很糟的
No. I wouldn't allow it. The taste would be terrible.
想像一下奥古斯特口味的巧克力胶糖
Can you imagine Augustus- flavored, chocolate- coated Gloop?
哟 没人会买的
No one would buy it.
我想让你带格鲁普女士带到软糖车间 好吗?
I want you to take Mrs. Gloop up to the Fudge Room, okay?
帮她找到她的儿子
Help her find her son.
用棒子把巧克力绞匀
Take a long stick and start poking around in the big chocolate- mixing barrel, okay?
旺卡先生?
Mr. Wonka?
为什么他们的歌里会有奥古斯特的名字 除非...?
Why would Augustus' name already be in the Oompa- Loompa song, unless...?
那是即兴创作的 每个人都会
Improvisation is a parlor trick. Anyone can do it.
你 小女孩 随便说点什么
You, little girl. Say something.
- 随便什么 - 口香糖
- Anything. - Chewing gum.
口香糖很恶心 口香糖我最不喜欢了
Chewing gum is really gross Chewing gum, I hate the most
看 一样的道理
See? Exactly the same.
不 不是的
No, it isn't.
你不应该嘀咕什么
You really shouldn't mumble.
因为我根本听不懂你在说什么
Because I can't understand a word you're saying.
继续参观吧
Now, on with the tour.
- 爷爷 欧伦比人是在开玩笑吧? - 他们当然是在开玩笑了
- Are the Oompa- Loompas really joking? - Of course they're joking.
那个小男孩没事的
That boy will be fine.
有什么好笑的?
What's so funny?
我想是可可豆引起的
I think it's from all those doggone cocoa beans.
你们知道吗 巧克力包含一种物质
Hey, by the way, did you guys know that chocolate contains a property...
触发情感的释放 使你产生被爱的感觉
...that triggers the release of endorphins? Gives one the feeling of being in love.
不要瞎说了
You don't say.
上船吧
All aboard.
开船
Onward!
给
Here.
尝尝这个吧 你看上去快饿死了
Try some of this. It'll do you good. You look starved to death.
- 味道真好 - 那是因为这是从瀑布来的
- It's great. - That's because it's mixed by waterfall.
瀑布是最重要的
The waterfall is most important.
与巧克力混和在一起 不停地搅拌巧克力 把它变得爽口、松脆
Mixes the chocolate, churns it up, makes it light and frothy.
- 顺便说一下 世界上还没有一个工厂... - 你已经说过了
- By the way, no other factory in the world... - You already said that.
- 你好像挺矮的 - 是的 但我们还是小孩
- You're all quite short, aren't you? - Well, yeah. We're children.
那也不是借口啊 我从来没像你这么小
Well, that's no excuse. I was never as short as you.
- 你曾经是 - 没有过 知道为什么吗?
- You were once. - Was not. Know why?
因为我清楚的 记得我戴了顶帽子
Because I distinctly remember putting a hat on top of my head.
看你短短的手臂 你永远都碰不到
Look at your short, little arms. You could never reach.
你还记得你的童年吗?
Do you even remember what it was like being a kid?
哦 孩子 我该记得吗
Oh, boy, do I.
我该记得吗?
Do I?
事实上 威利旺卡已经很久没有回忆他的童年了
In fact, Willy Wonka hadn't thought about his childhood for years.
不给糖就捣蛋!
Trick or treat!
都是谁啊?
Who do we have here?
鲁丝 维罗妮卡 特伦斯
Ruthie, Veronica, Terrance.
那毯子下的是...?
And who's that under the sheet?
小威利·旺卡
Little Willy Wonka.
威利·旺卡是著名牙医 威尔伯·旺卡
Willy Wonka was the son of the city's most famous dentist...
的儿子
... Wilbur Wonka.
威尔伯·旺卡牙医诊所
现在
Now...
让我们来看看这些蛀牙的东西吧
...let's see what the damage is this year, shall we?
焦糖
Caramels.
会粘在你的牙缝里的
They'd get stuck in your braces, wouldn't they?
棒棒糖
Lollipops.
我们叫它棒上的蛀虫
Ought to be called "cavities on a stick."
还有这些...
Then we have all this...
这些...
All this...
巧克力
...chocolate.
就在上周我看到 一本权威的医学杂志
You know, just last week, I was reading in a very important medical journal...
说有些孩子对巧克力过敏
...that some children are allergic to chocolate.
会让他们的鼻子变痒
Makes their noses itch.
也许我不过敏呢?
Maybe I'm not allergic.
我可以试一块
I could try a piece.
真的?
Really?
但为什么要冒险呢?
But why take a chance?
旺卡先生?
Mr. Wonka? Mr. Wonka?
- 我们要进隧道了 - 对
- We're headed for a tunnel. - Oh, yeah.
全速前进
Full speed ahead.
- 他们怎么看向哪里去 - 他们不能
- How can they see where they're going? - They can't.
他们根本不知道去哪里
There's no knowing where they're going.
打开灯
Switch on the lights!
大家注意了
People, keep an eye out.
我们要路过一间很重要的房间
We're passing some very important rooms here.
纯奶油
咖啡奶油
头发奶油
你用发油干什么?
What do you use hair cream for?
锁住水份
To lock in moisture.
- "鞭打"奶油? - 一点没错
- Whipped cream. - Precisely.
根本没道理啊
That doesn't make sense.
告诉你 小朋友
For your information, little girl...
生奶油不是"鞭打"奶油 除非它们被鞭打过
...whipped cream isn't whipped cream at all unless it's been whipped with whips.
人人都知道
Everybody knows that.
果冻豆
停船 我想给你们看点东西
Stop the boat. I wanna show you guys something.
发明室
这是整个工厂最重要的房间
Now, this is the most important room in the entire factory.
大家都尽情地玩吧 不过别碰任何东西
Now, everyone, enjoy yourselves, but just don't touch anything.
好吗? 去吧
Okay? Go on.
走吧
Go on, scoot.
旺卡先生 这是什么?
Hey, Mr. Wonka, what's this?
我告诉你
Let me show you.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是一种永不融化的糖球
These are Everlasting Gobstoppers.
是为没有零花钱的孩子造的
They're for children who are given very little allowance.
就算你含它一整年也不会变小
You can suck on it all year, and it'll never get any smaller.
- 是不是很聪明啊? - 就像口香糖一样
- Isn't that neat? - It's like gum.
不 口香糖是用来嚼的
No. Gum is for chewing.
如果你嚼这个
If you tried chewing one of these Gobstoppers...
牙齿都会断的
...you'd break all your little teeth off.
但是 这个味道是非常奇妙的
But they sure do taste terrific.
这是头发太妃糖
And this is Hair Toffee.
只要你吃了这个糖
You suck down one of these little boogers...
准确的来说 半个小时后...
...and in exactly half an hour...
大把的新头发会在你的小头上发芽
...a brand- new crop of hair will grow out over the top of your little noggin.
同时 会有新的头发、胡子长出来
And a mustache. And a beard.
- 谁会要胡子呢? - 恩...
- Who wants a beard? - Well...
乡村歌手、摇滚歌手和摩托飙车族
...beatniks, for one. Folk singers and motorbike riders.
那些摇滚啊、爵士啊、都是非常酷的 还有猫王
You know, all those hip, jazzy, super- cool, neat, keen and groovy cats.
这些都该放冰箱去了 你会跳舞吗?
It's in the fridge, daddy- o. Are you hep to the jive?
我弯腰你能拖住我吗? 我知道你行的
Can you dig what I'm laying down? I knew you could.
跟我来跳一个吧 小兄弟
Slide me some skin, soul brother.
但不幸的是 配方还不是很正确
Unfortunately, the mixture isn't right yet.
我昨天给一个欧比人吃了 结果...
Because an Oompa- Loompa tried some yesterday, and, well, he...
你今天感觉怎么样啊?
How are you today?
你看起来太好了
You look great.
看看这个吧
Watch this.
就这个东西?
You mean that's it?
你真的知道"这"是什么吗?
Do you even know what "it" is?
- 是口香糖 - 当然
- It's gum. - Yeah.
这是全宇宙上 最有不可想象最轰动的口香糖
It's a stick of the most amazing and sensational gum in the whole universe.
知道是为什么吗? 知道么?
Know why? Know why?
因为口香糖本身就是三道菜
Because this gum is a full three- course dinner all by itself.
怎么可能有人要那东西?
Why would anyone want that?
它会让所有的厨房和厨师关门
"It will be the end of all kitchens and all cooking.
一块小小的旺卡魔力口香糖 里面有你所有一天需要的营养
Just a little strip of Wonka's magic chewing gum and that is all you will...
早饭、午饭、晚饭
...ever need at breakfast, lunch and dinner.
这块口香糖是用 番茄汤、牛肉、蓝莓派做的
This piece of gum happens to be tomato soup, roast beef and blueberry pie."
这听起来好极了
It sounds great.
- 这太奇怪了 - 看上去是我喜欢的那种
- It sounds weird. - It sounds like my kind of gum.
我希望你不要吃 还有些成份....
I'd rather you didn't. There are still some things that are...
我可是全世界嚼口香糖冠军 我可什么都不怕
I'm the world- record holder in chewing gum. I'm not afraid of anything.
- 这味道怎么样啊 亲爱的? - 太好吃了
- How is it, honey? - It's amazing!
番茄汤的味道 我觉得到它正流过我的嗓子
Tomato soup. I can feel it running down my throat.
是啊 继续
Yeah. Spit it out.
- 小姑娘 你最好还是... - 味道在变呢
- Young lady, I think you'd better... - It's changing.
烤牛肉和烤土豆
Roast beef, with baked potato.
脆的皮还有黄油
Crispy skin and butter.
继续嚼 我的宝贝是第一个吃口香糖大餐的人
Keep chewing. My little girl's gonna be the first person to have a chewing- gum meal.
是啊 我只是有点关心....
Yeah. I'm just a little concerned about the...
蓝莓派和冰淇淋!
Blueberry pie and ice cream!
- 关心那个部分 - 她的鼻子怎么了?
- That part. - What's happening to her nose?
它正在变蓝
It's turning blue.
整个鼻子都成紫色了
Your whole nose has gone purple.
你在说什么呢?
What do you mean?
紫罗兰色 你成紫罗兰色了
Violet, you're turning violet.
- 她怎么了? - 我刚才就说这东西没完全做好
- What's happening? - Well, I told you I hadn't quite got it right.
是会有点奇怪的 尤其是到了甜点的时候
Because it goes a little funny when it gets to the dessert.
是那个蓝莓派造成的
It's the blueberry pie that does it.
噢 我非常抱歉
I'm terribly sorry.
妈妈 我是怎么了?
Mother? What's happening to me?
她在膨胀
She's swelling up.
好像蓝莓一样
Like a blueberry.
我在大概20个欧伦比人上做试验 但是每一个最后都变的像蓝梅一样
I've tried it on, like, 20 Oompa- Loompas, and each one ended up as a blueberry.
这太怪了
It's just weird.
我怎么能有个像蓝莓的女儿呢
But I can't have a blueberry as a daughter.
到时候她怎么去比赛呢?
How is she supposed to compete?
你可以把她带到国家展览会上去
You could put her in a county fair.
啊
Yeah, yeah
Yeah
仔细的听着 好好的听着
Listen close, and listen hard
这个维奥莉特的故事
To the tale of violet Beauregarde
这个文雅的小孩看上去不错
This gentle girl She sees no wrong
整天嚼啊嚼啊嚼
In chewing, chewing, chewing, chewing
Chewing, chewing all day long
一直嚼到后来
啊
Yeah
在她嚼的最后
She goes on chewing till, at last
她的咀嚼肌变大
Her chewing muscles grow so vast
她的脸颊变肿了
And from her face Her giant chin
就像一个小提琴
Sticks out just like a violin
整天嚼啊嚼啊嚼
Chewing, chewing all day long
嚼了一年又一年
For years and years she chews away
她的下颚越来越强壮
Her jaws get stronger every day
像一块巨大的口香糖
And with one great, tremendous chew
这可怜的女孩会有两个下巴
They bite the poor girl's tongue in two
这就是我们为什么这么费力
And that is why we try so hard
解救维奥莉特小姐
To save Miss violet Beauregarde
整天嚼啊嚼啊嚼
Chewing, chewing all day long
嚼啊嚼啊嚼
Chewing, chewing, chewing, chewing
Chewing, chewing all day long
整天嚼啊嚼啊嚼
旺卡先生!
Mr. Wonka!
请马上把维奥莉特滚到船上...
I want you to roll Miss Beauregarde into the boat...
完后 带她到榨汁车间
...and take her along to the Juicing Room at once, okay?
榨汁车间? 要在那儿做什么?
Juicing Room? What are they gonna do to her there?
他们要挤她
They're gonna squeeze her.
就像挤橙汁一样
Like a little pimple.
我们要马上把那些果汁挤出来
We gotta squeeze all that juice out of her immediately.
妈妈 快帮帮我啊
Mother, help me.
求你了
Please.
走吧
Come on.
我们继续啊
Let's boogie.
没有了小船 我们要花2倍的时间
Without the boat, we'll have to move double- time to keep on schedule.
太多东西要看呢
There's far too much to see.
- 旺卡先生 - 怎么了?
- Mr. Wonka? - Yeah?
为什么让人到工厂来?
Why did you decide to let people in?
那他们就可以参观工厂了啊
So they could see the factory, of course.
那为什么是现在呢? 又只有五个?
But why now? And why only five?
神秘礼物是什么? 谁会拿到呢?
What's the special prize, and who gets it?
最好的奖是意外奖
The best kind of prize is a surprise.
维奥莉特永远都会是个蓝莓吗?
Will Violet always be a blueberry?
不 也许会吧 我也不知道
No. Maybe. I don't know.
但这就是你每天都吃那口香糖的下场 那实在太恶心了
That's what you get from chewing gum all day. It's disgusting.
既然你这么讨厌口香糖 为什么要做呢?
If you hate gum so much, why do you make it?
提醒你啊 你不要再嘀咕什么了 我开始起鸡皮疙瘩了
Once again, you shouldn't mumble. It's starting to bum me out.
你还记得你第一次吃的糖果吗?
Can you remember the first candy you ever ate?
不
No.
事实上威利·旺卡的确 记得吃的第一块糖果
In fact, Willy Wonka did remember the first candy he ever ate.
坚果口感 很好吃 余味十足
对不起 我回忆起过去了
I'm sorry, I was having a flashback.
我明白了
I see.
那些回忆经常出现吗?
These flashbacks happen often?
越来越多了...
Increasingly...
今天
...today.
果仁间
啊 我知道这个房间是干什么的
This is a room I know all about.
你知道的旺卡先生 我是做坚果生意的
For you see, Mr. Wonka, I, myself, am in the nut business.
你也使用HeavyMax4000做分拣吗?
Are you using the Havermax 4000 to do your sorting?
不是的
No.
你真奇怪
You're really weird.
- 松鼠 - 是啊 松鼠
- Squirrels. - Yeah. Squirrels.
松鼠是专门用来脱壳的
These squirrels are specially trained to get the nuts out of shells.
为什么用松鼠 却不用欧伦比人呢?
Why use squirrels? Why not use Oompa- Loompas?
因为只有松鼠才能一次 就把整个果肉拿出来
Because only squirrels can get the whole walnut out almost every single time.
看 它们每次都先敲一下 看看里面有没坏
See how they tap them with their knuckles to make sure it's not bad?
看啊看啊
Oh, look. Look.
我想它的那颗是坏的
I think that one's got a bad nut.
爸爸 我要松鼠
Daddy, I want a squirrel.
给我一个那样的松鼠 我想要一个
Get me one of those squirrels. I want one.
维露卡 你已经有很多 可爱的宠物了
Veruca, dear, you have many marvelous pets.
我只是有一匹小马 两只小狗、四只猫和六只小兔子
All I've got at home is one pony and two dogs and four cats and six bunny rabbits...
两只金丝雀、两只绿鹦鹉 一只乌龟...
...and two parakeets and three canaries and a green parrot and a turtle...
和一只又笨又老的大颊鼠 我要一只松鼠!
...and a silly old hamster. I want a squirrel!
好的 亲爱的
All right, pet.
爸爸马上就给你一只松鼠
Daddy will get you a squirrel as soon as he possibly can.
我不要一般的松鼠 我要训练过的松鼠
But I don't want any old squirrel, I want a trained squirrel.
好的
Very well.
旺卡先生 一只松鼠你打算卖多少?
Mr. Wonka, how much do you want for one of these squirrels?
开个价吧
Name your price.
但那不是卖的 她不会有的
Oh, they're not for sale. She can't have one.
爸爸!
Daddy.
对不起 宝贝
I'm sorry, darling.
旺卡先生不讲道理
Mr. Wonka's being unreasonable.
如果你不给我弄一个 我自己去捉一个
If you won't get me a squirrel, I'll get one myself.
维露卡
Veruca.
小姑娘?
Little girl?
维露卡 快回来
Veruca, come back here at once.
维露卡
Veruca.
小姑娘
Little girl?
别碰那松鼠的坚果
Don't touch that squirrel's nuts.
会把它们惹火的
It'll make him crazy.
我就要你了
I'll have you.
维露卡
Veruca.
不要
No!
维露卡
Veruca!
让我找找钥匙
Let's find the key.
不是那把钥匙
Nope. Not that one.
- 爸爸 - 维露卡
- Daddy! - Veruca!
也不是这把
No. It's not that one.
是这把了
There it is.
不是这个
There it isn't.
爸爸 快让它们停下来
Daddy, I want them to stop.
它们在干什么?
What are they doing?
在看是不是坏的坚果
They're testing to see if she's a bad nut.
哦天呐 她是颗坏的
Oh, my goodness. She is a bad nut after all.
维露卡
Veruca!
爸爸!
Daddy!
它们带她去哪里啊?
Where are they taking her?
带她去坏的坚果该去的地方 坏的坚果都送去垃圾道了
Where all the other bad nuts go. To the garbage chute.
那个通道是去那里的?
Where does the chute go?
火化炉
To the incinerator.
不过别担心 只有星期二才开
But don't worry. We only light it on Tuesdays.
今天是星期二
Today is Tuesday.
但也有可能今天没点火
Well, there's always the chance they decided not to light it today.
现在 她很可能卡在垃圾道顶上了
Now, she may be stuck in the chute just below the top.
这样的话 你只要抓到她 把她拉上来就可以了
If that's the case, all you have to do is just reach in and pull her out.
好么?
Okay?
蛮横的维露卡·索尔特
Veruca Salt, the little brute
刚刚掉进垃圾道
Has just gone down the garbage chute
她不断地掉下去
And she will meet, as she descends
遇见一些不寻常的朋友
A rather different set of friends
比如说一个切下来的大鱼头
A fish head, for example, cut
今天早上从一条大比目鱼
This morning from a halibut
一个来自养蚝场的牡蛎
An oyster from an oyster stew
一块没人要吃的牛排
A steak that no one else would chew
还有其它一些东西
And lots of other things as well
气味实在太恶心
Each with its rather horrid smell
Horrid smell
这儿有维露卡的新朋友
These are veruca's newfound friends
她还在继续掉
That she will meet as she descends
那些是维露卡的新朋友
These are veruca's newfound friends
是谁不断宠爱她
Who went and spoiled her, who indeed?
到底是谁不断地满足她?
Who pandered to her every need?
谁把她变成一个坏小孩?
Who turned her into such a brat?
谁做了那些罪过?
Who are the culprits?
谁做的?
Who did that?
那个有罪的人现在很伤心
The guilty ones, now this is sad
就是她亲爱老妈妈和老爸爸
Are dear old Mum and loving Dad
哦 真的吗? 太好了
Oh, really? Oh, good.
我刚刚得到通知 火化炉坏了
I've just been informed that the incinerator's broken.
他们会落在三个星期的发臭的东西里
So there should be about three weeks of rotten garbage to break their fall.
那是好消息啊
Well, that's good news.
是啊
Yeah.
我们继续啊
Well, let's keep on trucking.
我不知道我为什么 一开始没有想到电梯
I don't know why I didn't think of this.
坐电梯参观整个厂最方便
The elevator's by far the most efficient way to get around the factory.
不可能这样一层层的参观
There can't be this many floors.
你怎么知道? 自做聪明的小子
How do you know, Mr. Smarty- Pants?
这可不是一般的上下电梯
This isn't just an ordinary up- and- down elevator, by the way.
这是一部能向左、向右、斜的
This elevator can go sideways, longways, slantways...
还有其他的方向的电梯 只要是你能想到的
...and any other ways you can think of.
只要按下按钮就行了
You just press any button and, whoosh, you're off.
哦 瞧那儿
Oh, look. Look.
先生女士们 欢迎来到菲齐山脉
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Fudge Mountain.
我最好还是不要谈这个了
I'd rather not talk about this one.
这是木偶医院和烧伤急救中心
This is the Puppet Hospital and Burn Center.
是新建的
It's relatively new.
行政办公室
The administration offices.
你好 多里斯
Hello, Doris.
危险
这里的东西有什么意义?
Why is everything here completely pointless?
糖果不需要有意义
Candy doesn't have to have a point.
所以它们是糖果
That's why it's candy.
这太白痴了
It's stupid.
糖果简直是浪费时间
Candy is a waste of time.
我儿子不能成为巧克力狂
No son of mine is going to be a chocolatier.
那我到别的地方去
Then I'll run away.
到瑞士、巴伐利亚
To Switzerland. Bavaria.
糖果之乡
The candy capitals of the world.
随便你
Go ahead.
但我不会在这等你回来
But I won't be here when you come back.
对不起 年轻人
Sorry, son.
我们晚上不开门
We're closing for the night.
万国旗展览场
我要选个房间
I wanna pick a room.
请便
Go ahead.
电视间
这个
Here.
快点带上这个 无论你做什么都不要摘下来
Put these on quick, and don't take them off whatever you do.
这些灯光能弄瞎你的眼睛
This light could burn your eyeballs right out of your skulls.
你不会想发生这种事吧
And we certainly don't want that, now, do we?
这个测试房间 是我最后也是最伟大的发明
This is the testing room for my very latest and greatest invention:
电视巧克力
Television Chocolate.
突然有一天我想
One day it occurred to me:
电视能把图像
"Hey, if television can break up a photograph...
分成千百万个部分 完后用空气传送
...into millions and millions of tiny pieces and send it whizzing through the air...
在最后的时候重新收集起来
...then reassemble it on the other end...
为什么我不能这样 传送巧克力呢?
...why can't I do the same with chocolate?
为什么不能通过电视 传送现成的巧克力呢?
Why can't I send a real bar of chocolate through the television, ready to be eaten?"
我将不会碰这个东西 我不要走这个方向
I'm not gonna touch it. I'm not going in that direction.
听上去不可能
Sounds impossible.
这根本就是不可能的
It is impossible.
你一点也不懂科学
You don't understand anything about science.
第一 波和粒子是不同的
First off, there's a difference between waves and particles.
第二 转换用的能量
Second, the amount of power it would take to convert energy in matter...
相当于九颗原子弹的能量
...would be like nine atomic bombs.
喳喳婆
Mumbler!
真的 我一点也听不懂你在说什么
Seriously, I cannot understand a single word you're saying.
好了 谢谢你
Okey- dokey.
好了 我要传送巧克力 用电视从这里...
I shall now send a bar of chocolate from one end of the room...
送到另一个房间
...to the other by television.
把巧克力拿过来
Bring in the chocolate.
必须得是很大块的巧克力 你知道在电视里人们的大小
It's gotta be real big because you know how on TV...
才这么点高 一样的道理
...you can film a regular- size man, and he comes out looking this tall?
同样的原理
Same basic principle.
巧克力不见了
It's gone.
我说过啦 它分成 千千万万的小块
Told you. That bar of chocolate is now rushing through the air above our heads...
飞走了
...in a million tiny little pieces.
跟我来
Come over here. Come on. Come on. Come on!
看屏幕
Watch the screen.
它来了
Here it comes.
看啊
Oh, look.
- 去拿啊 - 这只不过是荧幕图像
- Take it. - It's just a picture on a screen.
你吓坏了
Scaredy- cat.
那你去把它拿出来
You take it.
快 只要伸手进去拿出来就行了
Go on. Just reach out and grab it.
快啊
Go on.
我的天啊
Holy buckets.
吃吧
Eat it. Go on.
会很好吃的 一样的巧克力
It'll be delicious. It's the same bar.
只是传送的时候变小了点 仅此而已
It's just gotten a little smaller on the journey, that's all.
太好吃了
It's great.
太神奇了
It's a miracle.
想像一下 你在电视机看到广告...
So imagine, you're sitting at home watching television...
通过电视做交易 一个声音说
...and suddenly a commercial will flash onto the screen, and a voice will say:
说旺卡巧克力 全世界第一
"Wonka's chocolates are the best in the world.
如果你不相信 先尝一下
If you don't believe us, try one for yourself."
然后只要拿出巧克力就行了
And you simply reach out and take it.
这主意怎么样?
How about that?
那你还传送别的东西吗
So can you send other things?
比如早餐的麦片粥呢?
Say, like, breakfast cereal?
你知道早餐的麦片粥是怎么做的吗?
Do you have any idea what breakfast cereal's made of?
就像削铅笔削出来的 弯弯的木屑
It's those little curly wooden shavings you find in pencil sharpeners.
但你能通过电视传送吗?
But could you send it by TV if you wanted to?
- 我可以 - 那人呢?
- Of course I could. - What about people?
为什么要传送个人呢? 他们一点也不好吃
Well, why would I wanna send a person? They don't taste very good at all.
你知道你发明了什么吗? 电子运输器
Don't you realize what you've invented? It's a teleporter.
这是历史上最重要的发明啊
It's the most important invention in the history of the world.
但你所有的想象都是关于巧克力的
And all you think about is chocolate.
冷静 麦克
Calm down, Mike.
旺卡先生知道在干什么
I think Mr. Wonka knows what he's talking about.
哦是吗? 他根本就不知道
No, he doesn't. He has no idea.
你认为他是天才、但他是个白痴
You think he's a genius, but he's an idiot.
我可不是
But I'm not.
小朋友
Hey, little boy.
别碰我的按钮
Don't push my button.
他消失了
He's gone.
我们快去看电视 看有什么东西
Let's go check the television, see what we get.
希望他整个人都传过来了
I sure hope no part of him gets left behind.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
有时候只有一半能顺利传到
Well, sometimes only half of the little pieces find their way through.
如果你只能要一半的他 你会要哪一半?
If you had to choose only one half of your son, which one would it be?
你这算什么意思?
What kind of a question is that?
不要紧张 只不过问下而已
No need to snap. Just a question.
换个频道吧 我好想快点看到结果啊
Try every channel. I'm starting to feel a little anxious.
- 他在那儿 - 麦克
- There he is. - Mike.
最重要的是
The most important thing
我们学到...
That we've ever learned
我们学到很重要的有关孩子的一条
The most important thing we've learned As far as children are concerned
就是不要让孩子在电视机旁
Is never, never let them near The television set
或者干脆不要装这笨东西
Or better still just don't install The idiotic thing at all
千万不要让他们
Never, never let them Never, never let them
Never, never let them
千万不要让他们
它使人们的头脑生锈
It rots the senses in the head
杀死我们的想像力
It keeps imagination dead
混淆我们的思维
It clogs and clutters up the mind
使孩子盲目愚笨
It makes a child so dull and blind
愚笨
So dull, so dull
他连童话故事也不能听了
He can no longer understand A fairy tale, a fairyland
童话故事
A fairyland, a fairyland
他的大脑就像奶酪一样的软弱无能
His brain becomes as soft as cheese
他的思维腐朽僵硬
His thinking powers rust and freeze
他能看到 却不能思考
He cannot think, he only sees
在来看看麦克·提文
Regarding little Mike Teavee
我们很抱歉
We very much regret that we
很抱歉
Regret that we
我们只能等着瞧
Shall simply have to wait and see
等着瞧
Wait and see, wait and see
Wait and see, wait and see, wait and see
我们真的很抱歉
We very much regret that we
只能等着瞧
Shall simply have to wait and see
希望我们能把他变回来
If we can get him back his height
但不行的话
But if we can't
这样也不错
It serves him right
有人压住了他
Somebody grab him.
帮帮我
Help me.
谢天谢地 幸好没受伤
Oh, thank heavens. He's completely unharmed.
没受伤? 说什么胡话啊?
Unharmed? What are you talking about?
快用另一种方法把我变回去
Just put me back in the other way.
没有别的方法
There is no other way.
这是电视 不是电话 他们是不一样的
It's television, not telephone. There's quite a difference.
那你说该怎么办?
And what exactly do you propose to do about it?
我也不知道
I don't know.
但小孩很有弹性 他们可以无限的伸张
But young men are extremely springy. They stretch like mad.
- 把他带到太妃糖延展机去吧 - 太妃糖延展机?
- Let's go put him in the taffy puller. - Taffy puller?
那是我的主意
Hey, that was my idea.
他会变得很瘦长的?
Boy, is he gonna be skinny.
没错
Yeah.
太妃糖延展机
Taffy puller.
请把提文先生和这个小男孩
I want you to take Mr. Teavee and his...
带到太妃糖延展机
...little boy up to the taffy puller, okay?
把他拉长
Stretch him out.
我们继续参观吧
On with the tour.
还有很多东西要参观
There's still so much left to see.
现在 还剩下谁?
Now, how many children are left?
旺卡先生 只剩查理一个人了
Mr. Wonka, Charlie's the only one left now.
你说就剩你一个了?
You mean, you're the only one?
是的
Yes.
那其他孩子呢?
What happened to the others?
哦 可爱的小朋友 那你就是最后的获胜者了
Oh, my dear boy, but that means you've won.
我真心的祝贺你 真心的
Oh, I do congratulate you. I really do.
我真的很高兴
I'm absolutely delighted.
我一开始就知道会是你的 干得好
I had a hunch right from the beginning. Well done.
不过我们没时间玩了
Now, we mustn't dilly or dally.
天黑之前我们还有很多事要做
We have an enormous number of things to do before the day's out.
幸好我们有个超级电梯 可以加快进程
But luckily for us, we have the great glass elevator to speed things along...
可以加快进程
Speed things along.
快点
Come on.
往上飞出去
往上飞出去? 这是什么房间?
"Up and Out"? What kind of room is that?
等着瞧吧
Hold on.
天呐
Oh, my goodness.
我们还要再快点 不然我们无法穿越那里
We're gonna need to go much faster, otherwise we'll just never break through.
穿越哪里?
Break through what?
这颗按钮我多年没按了
I've been longing to press that button for years.
出发喽 向上出口
Well, here we go. Up and out.
- 你真的想...? - 对 真的
- But do you really mean...? - Yeah. I do.
可电梯是用玻璃做的
But it's made of glass.
我们会粉身碎骨的
It'll smash into a million pieces.
奥古斯特 不要再舔手指头了
Augustus, please don't eat your fingers.
可我实在太好吃了
But I taste so good.
看 妈妈 我变得更柔软了
Look, Mother. I'm much more flexible now.
是啊 可你成蓝色的了
Yes, but you're blue.
爸爸 我也要一个会飞的玻璃电梯
Daddy, I want a flying glass elevator.
你现在唯一能要的就是洗澡 不要吵了
Veruca, the only thing you're getting today is a bath, and that's final.
但我想要它!
But I want it!
你住哪儿?
Where do you live?
那儿 那个小房子里
Right over there. That little house.
他们什么时候才会回来啊?
What time do you think they'll be back?
我不知道 亲爱的
Hard to know, dear.
好像有人在敲门
I think there's someone at the door.
妈妈
Hi, Mom.
妈妈 爸爸 我们回来了
Mom. Dad. We're back.
- 查理 - 查理
- Charlie. - Charlie.
天呐
Goodness.
这是旺卡先生 是他送我们回来的
This is Willy Wonka. He gave us a ride home.
我看到了
I see that.
你们一定是孩子的...
You must be the boy's...
- 家长 - 对 - 就是
- Parents? - Yeah. - That.
他说查理赢了点东西
He says Charlie's won something.
不只是一些东西
Not just some something.
这些东西的东西 从来没有人有过的
The most "something" something of any something that's ever been.
我要把我的工厂送给查理
I'm gonna give this little boy my entire factory.
你在开玩笑吧
You must be joking.
不 我是认真的
No, really. It's true.
因为就在几个月前 也就是我每隔半年理一次发时
Because you see, a few months ago, I was having my semiannual haircut...
我发现了些奇怪的事
...and I had the strangest revelation.
在那根白头发中
In that one silver hair...
我看到了我职业生涯
... I saw reflected my life's work...
巧克力工厂 心爱的欧伦比人
... my factory, my beloved Oompa- Loompas.
我要是死了 谁来接我的班呢?
Who would watch over them after I was gone?
我意识到
I realized in that moment:
我一定得找个继承人
I must find a heir.
现在 我找到了 查理
And I did, Charlie.
就是你
You.
所以你才想出那些金券的
That's why you sent out the golden tickets.
欧伦比人是什么?
What are Oompa- Loompas?
我邀请了五个小孩
I invited five children to the factory...
其中坚持到最后的就是获奖者
...and the one who was the least rotten would be the winner.
就是你 查理
That's you, Charlie.
你觉得呢?
So, what do you say?
怎么样 你愿意放弃别的 和我一起在工厂里生活吗?
Are you ready to leave all this behind and come live with me at the factory?
当然啦
Sure. Of course.
我是说 如果我家里人也能去的话
I mean, it's all right if my family come too?
哦 亲爱的 他们当然不能去了
Oh, my dear boy, of course they can't.
你和一群老头子生活在一起
You can't run a chocolate factory...
怎么管理巧克力工厂
...with a family hanging over you like an old, dead goose. No offense.
懒得理你 贱人
None taken, jerk.
巧克力必须是自由自在的
A chocolatier has to run free and solo.
要跟随着梦想 才会有好的巧克力
He has to follow his dreams. Gosh darn the consequences.
看着我
Look at me.
我没家人 所以我很成功
I had no family, and I'm a giant success.
那如果我跟你去了工厂 就再也看不到家人了?
So if I go with you to the factory, I won't ever see my family again?
是啊 把这做为额外奖品吧
Yeah. Consider that a bonus.
那我是不会去的
Then I'm not going.
我不会离开我的家人的
I wouldn't give up my family for anything.
就算用全世界的巧克力来换
Not for all the chocolate in the world.
哦 我知道了
Oh, I see.
真是奇怪
That's weird.
那再加上所有的糖果呢?
There's other candy too besides chocolate.
对不起 旺卡先生 我还是待在这里吧
I'm sorry, Mr. Wonka. I'm staying here.
那真是...
Well, that's just...
太出乎意料
...unexpected...
太奇怪了
...and weird.
既然这样的话
But I suppose, in that case, I'll just...
那再见了
Goodbye, then.
你确定不会改变主意吗?
Sure you won't change your mind?
确定
I'm sure.
好吧 再见
Okay. Bye.
事情总会有好转的
Things are going to get much better.
奶奶总算是说对了一次
And for once, Grandma Georgina knew exactly what she was talking about.
第二天早晨 查理帮忙修好了屋子
The next morning, Charlie helped his parents fix the hole in the roof.
爷爷在床上躺了一天
Grandpa Joe spent the whole day out of bed.
他一点都不累
He didn't feel tired at all.
查理的爸爸在牙膏厂找到 一份更好的工作
Charlie's father got a better job at the toothpaste factory...
修理那些取代他的机器
... repairing the machine that had replaced him.
巴克特一家的生活 从没像现在这样好过
Things had never been better for the Bucket family.
但威利·旺卡的生活 却不是很顺利
The same could not be said for Willy Wonka.
我没法再专心下去了
I can't put my finger on it.
糖果是我一生中最确信的事
Candy's the only thing I was ever certain of...
但现在一点信心也没
...and now I'm just not certain at all.
我不知道该做什么口味 该尝试什么想法
I don't know which flavors to make or which ideas to try.
我现在就像个笨蛋
I'm second- guessing myself, which is nuts.
我总是凭感觉做糖果 我...
I've always made whatever candy I felt like, and I...
原理就是这样的 对吗?
That's just it, isn't it?
我一直凭感觉做糖果 我现在感觉很糟 所以做出来的糖果也很糟
I make the candy I feel like, but now I feel terrible, so the candy's terrible.
你真厉害
You're very good.
灰石咖啡厅
那个做巧克力的真可怜啊 什么王特...王豆...
Pity about that chocolate fellow, Wendell... Walter.
- 威利·旺卡 - 就是他
- Willy Wonka. - That's the one.
报纸上说这次的糖果卖得不好
Says here in the paper his new candies aren't selling very well.
也许这是他的报应
But I suppose maybe he's just a rotten egg who deserves it.
- 是啊 - 真的吗?
- Yep. - Oh, really?
你见过他?
You ever met him?
我见过
I did.
一开始我以为他是好人 后来我就不那么觉得了
I thought he was great at first, but then he didn't turn out so nice.
他的头发很搞笑
He also has a funny haircut.
没有!
I do not!
- 你在这里干什么? - 我感觉不好
- Why are you here? - I don't feel so hot.
你感觉不好的时候 什么会让你好过点?
What makes you feel better when you feel terrible?
我的家人
My family.
你为什么对我家人有意见?
What do you have against my family?
不是你的家人 只是...
It's not just your family. It's the whole idea of...
他们总是告诉你该做什么 不该做什么
They tell you what to do, what not to do...
这样不利于一个创造性的气氛
...and it's not conducive to a creative atmosphere.
通常他们只是为了保护你 因为他们爱你
Usually they're just trying to protect you because they love you.
如果你不相信 那你去问问
If you don't believe me, you should ask.
问谁? 我爸爸?
Ask who? My father?
没门
No way.
至少我不会
At least, not by myself.
那我跟你一块去怎么样?
You want me to go with you?
好主意啊
Hey. Hey, what a good idea. Yeah!
我提供交通工具
And you know what? I've got transport...
我下次一定得记住 停电梯的位置
I have to be more careful where I park this thing.
我想我们走错地方了
I think we've got the wrong house.
威尔伯旺卡牙医诊所
你预约了吗?
Do you have an appointment?
没 他早就该来看了
No. But he's overdue.
张嘴
Open.
看看坏了多少牙齿
Now, let's see what the damage is, shall we?
全球最大的工厂开幕了
旺卡在市中心开糖果店
旺卡推动地方经济发展
工厂开幕了
真不敢相信
Heavens.
我自从... 就没见过这么好的牙齿了
I haven't seen bicuspids like these since...
自从...
Since...
威利
Willy?
嗨 老爸
Hi, Dad.
这么多年了
All these years...
你从没有都没有蛀过牙?
...and you haven't flossed.
一次也没有
Not once.
那天后来 查理接受了 威利·旺卡的邀请
It was on this day that Willy Wonka repeated his offer to Charlie...
但有一个条件
... who accepted on one condition.
不好意思我们迟到了 外面在下暴风雪
Sorry we're late. We were brainstorming.
好像我听到了雷声
Thought I heard thunder.
- 和我们一起吃饭吧 威利 - 好的 谢谢
- You staying for dinner, Willy? - Yes, please.
我来摆盘子吧
I'll shuffle the plates.
你闻起来有股花生的味道
You smell like peanuts.
- 我喜欢花生 - 谢谢
- I love peanuts. - Oh, thank you.
你闻起来像...
You smell like...
老人和肥皂
...old people and soap.
我喜欢
I like it.
肘不要放桌子上面 查理
Elbows off the table, Charlie.
你觉得黑莓怎么样?
How do you feel about little raspberry kites?
还要甘草不要纤维
With licorice instead of string.
- 年轻人 吃饭的时候不讨论公事 - 对不起 妈妈
- Boys, no business at the dinner table. - Sorry, Mom.
我想你已经开始入门了 查理
I think you're on to something, though, Charlie.
最后 查理·巴克特 终于得到了巧克力工厂
In the end, Charlie Bucket won a chocolate factory.
而威利·旺卡得到了 一样更好的东西
But Willy Wonka got something even better:
一个家庭
A family.
可以确定的是
And one thing was absolutely certain:
他的生活从来没像现在这样甜美
Life had never been sweeter.